IELTS 20 published by Cambridge University Press and Assessment 2025. This recording
is copyright.
Test 1. This is the IELTS listening test. You will hear a number of different recordings
and you will have to answer questions on what you hear. There will be time for you to read
the instructions and questions and you will have a chance to check your work. All the
recordings will be played once only. The test is in four parts. At the end of the test you
will be given 10 minutes to transfer your answers to an answer sheet.
Now turn to part 1. Part 1. You will hear a woman asking a friend for restaurant recommendations.
Next you have some time to look at questions 1 to 4.
Now listen carefully and answer questions 1 to 4.
I've been meaning to ask you for some advice about restaurants. I need to book somewhere
to celebrate my sister's 30th birthday and I liked the sound of that place you went to
for your mum's 50th.
The Junction. Yeah, I'd definitely recommend that for a special occasion. We had a great
time there. Everyone really enjoyed it.
Where is it again? I can't remember.
It's on Grayson Street, only about a two-minute walk from the station.
Oh, that's good. I'd prefer not to have to drive anywhere. But I don't want to have to
walk too far either.
Yes, the location's perfect, but that's not necessarily why I'd recommend it. The food's
amazing. If you like fish, it's probably the best restaurant in town for that. It's always
really fresh and there are lots of interesting dishes to choose from. But all the food is
good there.
Is it really expensive?
It's certainly not cheap, but for a special occasion I think it's fine. It's got a great
atmosphere and before dinner you can go up on the roof and have a drink. It's really
nice up there, but you need to book. It's very popular as the views are spectacular.
Sounds good. So that's definitely a possibility then. Is there anywhere else you can think
of?
If you want somewhere a bit less formal, then you could try Paloma.
Where's that? I haven't heard of it.
No, it's quite new. It's only been open a few months, but it's got a great reputation
already. It's in a really beautiful old building on Bow Street.
Oh, I think I know where you mean. Right beside the cinema?
Yes, that's it. I've only been there a couple of times, but I was really impressed. The
chef used to work at Don Felipe's apparently. I was really sorry when that closed down.
So is all the food they serve Spanish then?
Yes. You can get lots of small dishes to share, which always works really well if you're
in a group.
Worth thinking about.
Yes. There's a lively atmosphere and the waiters are really friendly. The only thing is that
you need to pay a £50 deposit to book a table.
A lot of restaurants are doing that these days. I should have a look at the menu to
check there's a good choice of vegetarian dishes. A couple of my friends have stopped
eating meat.
Not sure. I'd say the selection of those would be quite limited.
Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions five
to ten.
Now listen and answer questions five to ten.
I've just thought of another idea. Have you been to the Audley?
No, don't think I've heard of it. How's it spelt?
A-U-D-L-E-Y. You must have heard of it. There's been a lot about it in the press.
I don't tend to pay much attention to that kind of thing. So where is it exactly?
It's in that hotel near Baxter Bridge on the top floor.
Oh, the views would be incredible from up there.
Yeah, I'd love to go. I can't think of the chef's name, but she was a judge on that TV
cookery show recently, and she's written a couple of cookery books.
Oh, Angela Frain.
That's the one. Anyway, it's had excellent reviews from all the newspapers.
That would be a memorable place for a celebration.
Definitely. Obviously it's worth going there just for the view,
but the food is supposed to be really special.
She only likes cooking with local products, doesn't she?
Yes. Everything at the restaurant has to be sourced within a short distance,
and absolutely nothing flown in from abroad.
I imagine it's really expensive, though.
Well, you could go for the set lunch. That's quite reasonable for a top-class restaurant.
Thirty pounds a head. In the evening, I think it'd be more like fifty pounds.
At least that, I should think. But I'm sure everyone would enjoy it.
It's not the kind of place you leave feeling hungry, though, is it? With tiny portions?
No, the reviews I've read didn't mention that. I imagine they'd be average.
Well, that's all great. Thanks so much.
Thank you for watching!
Please subscribe to my channel!